Aaron Niskin

3415 Chase Ave — Miami Beach, FL 33140

(305) 894-6475 • ⋈ aaron@niskin.org • 🖆 aaron.niskin.org

HR Department October 3, 2016

Blackrock 40 East 52nd Street 10022 New York, NY

Dear Sir or Madam,

When my professor, Dr. Gary Kalmanovich, told me about Jacopo, a bit about his research, and the internship possiblilty at Blackrock, my interest was piqued. Some people find satisfaction in learning a thing and sticking with it. I am not one of those people. I prefer to live on the edge of my own understanding, constantly venturing further into the unknown. This outlook has resulted in my taking nearly every Math course my alma mater had to offer, and my desire to enter the field of Finance (the undisputed king of the unknown). This preference is not solely a personally beneficial stance, but rather has lead to many workplace improvements.

As an example, I recall one instance from my Army days. For several missions, we would perform our standard communications checks without any issues, but later on in the mission the company would be split into separate "nets". Our Commo Sergeant said this was an unavoidable phenomena, which didn't sound reasonable to me. I (a Private at the time) conducted my own investigation. It turns out that these radios use something called "frequency hop encryption", which is to say that they change frequency according to a predetermined sequence and the time. The time, however, is the crux. Each time a radio "que's the mic", a receiving radio's time is synced to the sender. If, as was the case with us, two radios are separated for a few minutes by a land barrier, it's likely that net will be split due to the random drift. I discovered that this, being a known problem, has a solution and I re-engineered our company radios and we never had that problem again.

I believe my penchant for learning, problem solving, and optimizing things would make me a valuable memember of the team at Blackrock. I realize that to say this will be a challenge would be putting it lightly, but that fact only serves to motivate me further. I am looking forward to many late nights with textbooks and my computer, finding ways to optimize code, etc.

Thank you very much for your time and consideration. If you have any questions and or comments, please feel free to contact me at any time.

Sincerely yours,

Aaron Niskin

Attached: Resumé

Aaron Niskin

3415 Chase Ave - Miami Beach, FL 33140

☎ (305) 894-6475 • ⊠ aaron@niskin.org • ७ aaron.niskin.org

Skills and Languages

Advanced: JAVASCRIPT, HTML, PYTHON*, R* | Spanish

Intermediate: Clojure, Scheme, Hoplon, CSS, MySQL, PostgreSQL, NodeJS | Hebrew

Basic: JAVA, HASKELL, MONGODB, LATEX, MATLAB, OCTAVE | German

*Projected - based on current workload

Education

New College of Florida Sarasota Master's In Data Science 2016-(2018)

Florida International University

Miami

Bachelor of Science | Mathematics Minors | Physics and English 2012-2015

- Graduated Cum Laude GPA 3.64 (3.79 in major)
- Dean's List (6 times)

Miami Dade College Miami Associate of Arts 2010-2011

- Graduated with Honors GPA 3.74 out of 4.00
- Dean's List (5 times)
- Physics Award

Experience

Florida Vocation Institute

Miami

Computer Science Instructor

2015-2016

- Taught and created syllabi for courses in HTML, CSS, CSS-Frameworks, JavaScript, SQL, MongoDB, NodeJS, Functional-Programming, and Basic-Logic
- Created a free online course intended to teach aspiring students about the above subjects through interesting projects (currently live at www.fvi-grad.com)

Math-Busters (www.Math-Busters.com)

Miami

Co-founder and Math/Science/Computing Tutor

2010-2015

- Co-founded a successful income generating tutoring company (www.Math-Busters.com)
- Tutored all levels of students from Elementary School to upper-level University students

Infantryman

1-38 Infantry Regiment, 4/2 ID, US Army

Fort Lewis. WA

2006-2009

- Deployed to Iraq for OIF V from 2007-2008
- Held Team Leader, Rifleman, M-240B Machine Gunner, M-249 SAW gunner, RTO, Grenadier, and Marksman positions
- Combat Lifesaver certification
- Fought forest fires in Winthrop, Washington.

478th Civilian Affairs Battalion, US Army

Perrine, FL

Civil Affairs Specialist

2004-2006

- Trained at the John F. Kennedy Special Warfare Center and School in Fort Bragg, NC for 6 months.
- Obtained Secret Clearance